<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Micro-architectural attacks | Marco Guarnieri</title>
    <link>https://mguarnieri.github.io/tag/micro-architectural-attacks/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://mguarnieri.github.io/tag/micro-architectural-attacks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Micro-architectural attacks</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://mguarnieri.github.io/media/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Micro-architectural attacks</title>
      <link>https://mguarnieri.github.io/tag/micro-architectural-attacks/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hardware/software co-design for secure speculation</title>
      <link>https://mguarnieri.github.io/project/hwsw-codesign/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mguarnieri.github.io/project/hwsw-codesign/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Speculative execution attacks, such as the recent Spectre attacks, are a recent
class of security threats that affect almost all modern processors (that is,
millions of IT systems). These attacks exploit the hardware side-effects of a
CPU optimization called speculative execution to break fundamental security
assumptions on how programs are executed and to leak sensitive information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hardware/software co-design is an essential principle for building practical
systems that are secure against these attacks. Following this principle,
hardware and software should collaborate to thwart speculative execution
attacks. Hardware platforms should provide precise security guarantees and
expose control on the internal microarchitectural state. Software, instead,
should leverage these guarantees to achieve end-to-end security. Unfortunately,
we currently lack foundations, guiding principles, and tools for co-design for
security.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;goals&#34;&gt;Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project will develop foundations, models, and tools for enabling co-design for
secure speculation. The project will revolve around the notion of
hardware/software security contract, an abstraction enabling the distribution of
security obligations between hardware and software. The project will provide
developers with languages for specifying security contracts as well as
techniques for automatically determining whether proposals for secure
speculation effectively prevent speculative execution attacks.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reasoning about speculative execution attacks</title>
      <link>https://mguarnieri.github.io/project/speculative-execution/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mguarnieri.github.io/project/speculative-execution/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Speculative execution attacks, like the recent Spectre attacks, exploit the
persistent microarchitectural side-effects of speculatively executed
instructions. These attacks affect all modern general-purpose CPUs and
pose a serious threat against platforms with multiple tenants. However, we
still lack a precise characterization of security against speculative
execution attacks. Such a characterization is a prerequisite for reasoning
about the effectiveness and security of countermeasures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;goals&#34;&gt;Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project&amp;rsquo;s goals are (1) building the theoretical foundations for reasoning
about speculative execution attacks, (2) developing techniques for
detecting speculative leaks (or prove their absence), and (3) analyzing
the security of (hardware and software) Spectre&amp;rsquo;s countermeasures.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automatically learning micro-architectural models</title>
      <link>https://mguarnieri.github.io/project/learning-uarch-models/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mguarnieri.github.io/project/learning-uarch-models/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Understanding the timing behavior of modern CPUs is crucial for optimizing code
and for ensuring timing-related security and safety properties. Unfortunately,
the timing behavior of today’s high-performance processors depends on subtle and
poorly documented details of their micro-architecture, which has triggered
laborious efforts from researchers to build models of different components.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;goals&#34;&gt;Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project aims at constructing techniques and tools for automatically
inferring and learning high-level models of micro-architectural components (like caches and
prefetchers) directly from timing measurements.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
